Judith A. Jance Papers 1927-2006 (bulk 1991-2005)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Judith A. Jance Papers 1927-2006
MS 419
Judith A. Jance
Papers, 1927-2006 (bulk 1991-2005). This collection is comprised of the papers of J.A. Jance. The bulk of the material relates to her prolific literary career. Items include correspondence; published and unpublished writings including manuscripts, articles, short stories, adaptations and speeches; printed materials including book covers, mystery magazines and newsletters and news clippings; correspondence; photographs; audiovisual material including audiotapes, videocassette tapes and computer files; and objects including plaques, a computer and promotional items.
21.25 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None
Biographical Note
J.A. (Judith Ann) Jance was born in Watertown, South Dakota in 1944 but grew up in Bisbee, Arizona. After graduating from Bisbee High School, Ms. Jance attended the University of Arizona and graduated in 1966 with a Bachelor's of Arts Degree in English and Secondary Education. In 1967 she married her first husband, a fellow graduate from the University of Arizona. She worked as an English teacher at Pueblo High School until 1968. She received a Master of Education in Library Science in 1970 and became a librarian in the Indian Oasis School District on the Tohono O'odham reservation. While living on the reservation where both she and her husband taught, Ms. Jance's husband received a ride home from a serial killer who eventually stalked the couple. Mr. Jance was able to help the police identify the suspect which led to his arrest.
In 1980 Ms. Jance divorced her husband and moved to Seattle, Washington with her two children. There she sold life insurance before marrying her second husband in 1985. In 1982, Ms. Jance began writing her first true crime novel based on her experience with the serial murderer on the Tohono O'odham reservation which was never published. Ms. Jance then wrote her first mystery fiction novel which was published in 1985. After publishing her novel Ms. Jance turned to writing full time. J.A. Jance is a prolific author who has written mystery novels in several series including the J.P. Beaumont, Joanna Brady and Ali Reynolds series as well as several thrillers, a book of poetry based on her marriage to an alcoholic, and several books in a children's personal safety series.
Organization
This collection is organized into 7 series. The Writings and Audiovisual series each contain three subseries.
Series 1: Biographical Files, 1927-2006
Series 2: Correspondence, 1973-2006
Series 3: Writings, 1966-2005
Subseries 1: Manuscripts, 1984-2005
Subseries 2: Articles and Short Stories, 1984-2005
Subseries 3: Miscellaneous, 1993-1996
Series 4: Printed Materials, 1985-2005
Series 5: Photographs, 1985-2005
Series 6: Audio Visual Materials, 1986-2005
Subseries 1: Audiotapes, 1987-2005
Subseries 2: Videotapes, 1986-2005
Computer Files, 1987-1997
Objects, 1962-2001
Scope and Content Note
Papers, 1927-2006 (bulk 1991-2005). This collection consists of materials which document the literary career of mystery writer J.A. Jance. The bulk of the material is comprised of drafts of manuscripts, articles and short stories as well as printed materials including news clippings and various mystery newsletters and magazines. The collection also contains correspondence, photographs, audio visual materials and objects.
Related Material
Access Terms
Jance, Judith A.-- Archives.
American fiction-- 20th century.
Authors, American-- 20th century-- Archives.
American literature-- Southwestern States.
American literature--Northwestern States.
Seattle (Wash.)-- Fiction.
Bisbee (Ariz.)--Fiction.
Container List
- Biographical Files. 1927-2006
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains biographical materials associated with J.A. Jance. It includes certificates, news clippings, receipt of an honorary degree and reports from high school assignments.
  - Biographical Materiasl. nd, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Certificates. nd, 1969-2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General. 1927-2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Honorary Degree. 2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Interview. nd (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Oregon Shakespeare Festival. 2000-2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - School Assignments. nd (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence. 1973-2006
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains letters from various editors, publishers and fans relating to J.A. Jance's literary works as well as letters arranging Ms. Jance's tours and events schedule.
  - Editors and Publishers. 1984-2005 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Events and Appearances. 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Events and Appearances. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Events and Appearances. 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Events and Appearances. 1995 (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
  - Events and Appearances. 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Events and Appearances. 1997 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Events and Appearances. 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
  - Events and Appearances. 1999 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Events and Appearances. 2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Events and Appearances. 2001 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Events and Appearances. 2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Events and Appearances. 2003 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Events and Appearances. 2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Events and Appearances. 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fan Mail. nd, 1985-1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fan Mail. 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Fan Mail. 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fan Mail. 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fan Mail. 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fan Mail. 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Fan Mail. 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - General. nd, 1973-1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - General. 1997-2001 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - General. 2002-2005 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Invitations. 1986-1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Invitations. 1995-2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Invitations. 2001-2006 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Thank You Letters. nd (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Thank You Letters. 1988-1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Thank You Letters. 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Thank You Letters. 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Thank You Letters. 2001-2005 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Writings 1966-2005
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains the published and unpublished writings of J.A. Jance. The Writings series is divided into three subseries:
  Manuscripts (1984-2005) contains drafts of manuscripts.
  Articles and Short Stories (1966-2005) contains drafts of articles and short stories for magazines and anthologies as well as personal editorial responses to newspaper articles.
  Miscellaneous (1993-1996) contains film and radio adaptations of J.A. Jance's novels as well as a speech given by Jance.
  - Subseries: Manuscripts 1984-2005
    - After the Fire. 2001 (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
    - Breach of Duty. 1999 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
    - By Reason of Insanity. nd (Box 3, Folder 12-15)
    - By Reason of Insanity - Synopsis Included. nd (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
    - By Reason of Insanity- Synopsis Included. nd (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Day of the Dead. 2004 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - Dead to Rights. 1996 (Box 4, Folder 4-6)
    - Dead Wrong. 2005 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - Desert Heat. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
    - Devil's Claw. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 11-16)
    - Edge of Evil. 2005 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
    - Exit Wounds. 2003 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
    - Failure to Appear. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
    - Hour of the Hunter. nd (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    - Hour of the Hunter. 1991 (Box 5, Folder 10-12)
    - Indecent Exposure. nd (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
    - Indian Time. nd (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
    - It's Not Your Fault. 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Lest Ye Be Judged. nd (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Long Time Gone. nd (Box 6, Folder 6-9)
    - Long Time Gone. 2005 (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
    - Lying in Wait. 1994 (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
    - Outlaw Mountain. 1999 (Box 6, Folder 14-16)
    - Partner in Crime. 2001 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
    - Partner in Crime. 2002 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Rattlesnake Crossing. 1998 (Box 7, Folder 3-5)
    - Shoot/Don't Shoot. 1994 (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
    - Skeleton Canyon. nd (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
    - Skeleton Canyon. 1997 (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
    - Taking the Fifth. nd (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
    - Taking the Fifth. 1987 (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
    - Tombstone Courage. nd (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
    - Tombstone Courage. nd (Box 8, Folder 1-7)
    - Tombstone Courage. 1994 (Box 8, Folder 8-10)
    - Until Proven Guilty. nd (Box 8, Folder 11-13)
    - Walking Wounded. 2002 (Box 8, Folder 14-16)
    - Welcome Home Stranger. 1985 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Without Due Process. 1993 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Subseries: Articles and Short Stories 1966-2005
    - The Case of the London Cabbie. 2005 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Crimes of the Heart. 1996 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - The Duel. 1991 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Fathers and Daughters. 1999 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - A Flash of Chrysanthemum. nd (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - A Game of Cat and Mouse. 1972 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Gone, but Not Forgotten. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Greenway Librarian- Editorial. nd (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Highest, Best Use. nd (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - How I Wrote Dead to Rights. 1996 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - JA Jance: On Her Three Bisbees. 2000 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - The Long Slide Home. 2004 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Mandy: "Free to a Good Home." 1992 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Naked Came the Phoenix. 2001 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - On Writing Hour of the Hunter. 1992 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Periods of Partial Clearing. 1993 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Pima A Cooperative: The Dorm for Individuals. 1966 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Second Fiddle. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Skeleton Canyon Then and Now. 1997 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Untitiled. 1998 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - The Who in Whodunits. 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Witness. 2004 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - The Wrtiting Bug. 2004 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - You-Editorial. 1987 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Subseries: Miscellaneous 1993-1996
    - Adaptation- Hour of the Hunter. nd (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Adaptation- Until Proven Guilty. 1996 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Speech- Storytelling: It's Not Just for Kids. 1993 (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Printed Materials. 1985-2005
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains printed materials including book covers for J.A. Jance's novels, programs for various mystery writers' events, mystery fiction magazines and newsletters and publicity materials including news clippings and event posters.
  - Boucheron. 1992-1994 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Book Cover Designs. nd (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Book Covers- Breach of Duty. 1999 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Book Covers- Birds of Prey. 2002 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Book Covers- Day of the Dead. 2005 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Book Covers- Dead to Rights. 1997 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Book Covers- Desert Heat. 1993-2002 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Book Covers- Devil's Claw. 2001 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Book Covers- Dismissed with Prejudice. 1989 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Book Covers- Edge of Evil. 2006 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Book Covers- Exit Wounds. 2004 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Book Covers- Failure to Appear. 1989 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Book Covers- Hour of the Hunter. 1990-2003 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Book Covers- Improbable Cause. 1987-2003 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Book Covers- Injustice for All. 1986 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Book Covers- Kiss of the Bees. 2001 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Book Covers- Long Time Gone. 2005 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Book Covers- Lying in Wait. 2005 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Book Covers- Minor in Possession. 1990 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Book Covers- A More Perfect Union. 1988-2003 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Book Covers- Mothers and Daughters. 1998 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Book Covers- Name Withheld. 1997 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Book Covers- Outlaw Mountain. 2000 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Book Covers- Paradise Lost. 2002 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Book Covers- Partners in Crime. 2002 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Book Covers- Payment in Kind. 1991 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Book Covers- Rattlesnake Crossing. 1999 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Book Covers- Sentenced to Die. 2005 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Book Covers- Skeleton Canyon. 1998 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Book Covers- Taking the Fifth. 1987 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Book Covers- Tombstone Courage. 1995-2003 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Book Covers- Trial by Fury. 1986-2003 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Book Covers- Shoot/Don't Shoot. 2003 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Book Covers- Until Proven Guilty. 1985 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Book Covers- Without Due Process. 1993 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Left Coast Crime. 1991 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Magazines- The Armchair Detective. 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Magazines- The Armchair Detective. 1995 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Magazines- The Armchair Detective. 1995 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Magazines- The Armchair Detective. 1996 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Magazines- Murderous Intent. 1995 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Magazines- Mystery Readers Journal. 1994 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Magazines- Mystery Scenes. 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Magazines- Mystery Scene. 1996-1999 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Magazines- New Mystery. 1994 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Magazines- Over My Dead Body!. 1994 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Mystery Writers of America- Directory. 1986-2005 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters- Book Passage. 1999-2005 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters- Book News from the Poisoned Pen. 1991-2001 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters- Deadly Pleasures. 1994 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters- The Dinsmore Patch. 1994 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters- International Footprint Association Chapter 17 News. 2001-2004 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters- Mysterious Women. 1996-1999 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters- Mystery Lovers Bookshop. 1994-2001 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters- Mystery News. 1997 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters- A Pocket Full of Crime. 1993 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters- The Poison Pen. 1998-2005 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Newsletters- Seattle Mystery Bookshop. 2001 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters- Sisters in Crime. 1992-2005 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Newsletters- The Third Degree. 1987-2005 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Posters. nd (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Publicity- Avon Books. 1996-1999 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Publicity- Avon Books. 1999-2003 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Publicity- Newsclippings. nd, 1984-1993 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Publicity- Newsclippings. 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Publicity- Newsclippings. 1996 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Publicity- Newclippings. 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Publicity- Newsclippings. 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Publicity- Newsclippings. 2001-2002 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Publicity- Newsclippings. 2003-2005 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Publicity- Promotional Packets. 1989-2004 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Publicity- Publisher's Weekly. 1990 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Publicity- Severn House. 1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Sisters in Crime- Books in Print. 1995-1999 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Sisters in Crime- Books in Print. 2001-2004 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Sisters in Crime- Directory. 1997-2005 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Photographs 1985-2004
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains photographs of J.A. Jance at various events. Also included are several personal photographs (mostly unidentified).
  - General. nd, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Jance, Judith. nd, 1998-2004 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Jance, Judith - Book Signings. nd (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Audiovisual Materials 1986-2005
  Arrangement: Chronological. This series contains audiovisual materials pertaining to Ms. Jance's literary career. The Audiovisual Materials series is divided into three subseries:
  Audiotapes (1987-2005) contains audiocassette tapes and compact disks. Included are various interviews and speaking events. Some materials are in Dutch.
  Videotapes (1986-2005) contains VHS tapes of various interviews and speaking events.
  Computer Files (1987-1997) contains floppy disks (3 1/2 and 5 1/2 inch disks) of computer programs mostly for Ms. Jance's 1983 Eagle computer as well as drafts of manuscripts.
  - Subseries: Audiotapes 1987-2005
    Audiocassette Tapes
    - Helen Pollack Ramp Dedication. nd (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - J.A. Jance Seminar Tapes (7). 1987 (Box 12, Folder 2-8)
    - J.A. Jance Interview- Dick Curtis Show- KVI- 2/4/88. 1988 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Third Thursday Reading Series 2-21-91. 1991 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Radioprogramma Passages Passanyen, Uitgezoden 27 April 1993, Deel 4 van de serie over Female Crime Writers, Vandaag: een interview van Ineke van den Bergen met de Amerikaanse schrijfster J.A. Jance. 1993 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Avon Books, Dead to Rights R:30, Bennette Book Adv. 5/22/96. 1996 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Writer or Promoter? J.A. Jance, Emerald City Writers' Conference, October 11-12, 1997. 1997 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Connie Swanson. 1997 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Rattlesnake Crossing, J.A. Jance. 1998 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - 50 Years/ J.A. Jance 11/98. 1998 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - J.A. Jance King 98/FM Radio Spot, 11/98. 1998 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - J.A. Jance/YWCA Benefit 1/99. 1999 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - J.A. Jance KWCD 92.3 April 12, 1999. 1999 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - J.A. Jance, Mornings with Kelly, September 15, 1999. 1999 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - J.A. Jance April 12, 1999. 1999 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - J.A. Jance on JPR 9-12-00. 2000 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Harper Collins Radio Kiss of the Bees: 30, 12/13/00. 2000 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Break Out the Muscle: High Octane Thrillers, Los Angeles Time Festival of Books. 2001 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Harper Collins Radio Devil's Claw: 30, 6/20/01. 2001 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - 01...Keynote Speaker: J.A. Jance. 2002 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - OB...On Getting Over the Mountain to Yon- J.A. Jance (2). 2002 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - J.A. Jance, Mornings with Kelly, September 15, 1999. 2004 (Box 12, Folder 28-29)
      Compact Disks
    - KJZZ Growing Up in Bisbee, J.A. Jance Arizona Week Feb. 11, 2002, 5:30 AM and 7:30 AM. 2002 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Jolt AM 1330 J.A. Jance Tucson Today (2). 2004 (Box 12, Folder 31-32)
    - Book Talk WYPL Memphis Sept 04 J.A. Jance Day of the Dead. 2004 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Let's Talk Books, Episode 1, 5/19/05. 2005 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Subseries: Videotapes 1986-2005
    - Good Company January 23. 1986 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Interview at Doghouse, June 17, 1987. 1987 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - JA Jance AM Northwest KATU July 31, 1987. 1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - JA Jance (Author) at Juanita High School October 27, 1988. 1988 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - 12-91 JAJ NW AFT. 1991 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - The Mystery Writer: J.A. Jance (2). 1993 (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
    - J.A. Jance Interview Ch. 7 April 14, 1994. 1994 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Hour Northwest May 11, 1994 (4). 1994 (Box 13, Folder 9-12)
    - J.A. Jance 'CBS This Morning' 4/3/95. 1995 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Women in Communication, Inc. J.A. Jance. 1996 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Book Talk August '97: Scottsdale Public Library Book Talk. 1997 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - The Criminal Calendar Carolyn Wheat/J.A. Jance: Poisoned Pen and Scottsdale Public Library Presentation of the Criminal Calendar. 2000 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Northwest Week Mondays and Fridays @ 7 PM on KBTC/PBS Guests: J.A. Jance 04/2001. 2001 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - J.A. Jance Arizona Illustrated KUAT (Ch. 6) 6:30 PM Airdate: 08/29/01. 2001 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - JA Jance Tribute to Girl Scout Leaders LaVerne Williams and Rose Bennett. 2002 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Partner in Crime Clips: AM Northwest, Northern Kentucky Magazine ICN6, WDTN 12 PM News, Ohio, August 14, 2002. 2002 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - J.A. Jance KOLO-TV October 25, 2002. (2) 2002 (Box 13, Folder 21-22)
    - Authors visiting Des Moines: J.A. Jance. 2003 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Connie Martinson Talks Books J.A. Jance Exit Wounds. 2003 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Judy's Speech. 2003 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Between the Lines- Channel 8 Paradise Lost J.A. Jance 08/23/01. 2001 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Northwest Afternoon KOMO-TV ABC 4 Bestselling Author J.A. Jance 9/10/2003. 2003 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - J.A. Jance Interview Northwest Afternoon, 9/10/03. (4) 2003 (Box 13, Folder 28-31)
    - Writers Out Loud Oklahoma State University- Tulsa. 2005 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Subseries: Computer Files, 1987-1997
    - Applications- Cover Com. nd (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Applications- CPM. nd (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Applications- Data Disk Backup. 1997 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Applications- DOS. nd (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Applications- Eaglecalc. nd (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Applications- Spellbinder. nd (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Applications- Spellbinder Manual. 1985 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Applications- System Disk. nd (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Applications- The Word (Word Count). nd (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Applications- Word Processing Backup. nd (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Applications- Word Star. nd (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Applications- Wordperfect 4.2. nd, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Applications- WP. nd (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous- ASGTAMI. 1997 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous- Childrens. nd (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous- David P. nd (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous- Unidentified. nd (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Writings- ABOW. 1997 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Writings- CA. nd (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Writings- DDI. nd (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Writings- HOTH ( Hour of the Hunter). nd (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Writings- HOTH ( Hour of the Hunter). nd, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Writings- IC ( Improbably Cause). nd, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Writings- IFA ( Injustice for All). nd, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Writings- PIK ( Payment in Kind). nd (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Writings- Poems. nd (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Writings- TBF ( Trial by Fury). nd, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Writings- TTF ( Taking the Fifth). nd (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Writings- UI. nd (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Writings- UPG ( Until Proven Guilty). nd, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 30)
- Objects, 1962-2001
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains plaques and other objects relating to the promotion of Ms. Jance's literary works. Also included is Ms. Jance's original computer used to write her first novels.
  - Buttons; "Save the Doghouse." nd (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Buttons; Sheriff Joanna Brady. nd (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Medals; American Legion. 1962 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous; Cup-Starbucks coffee with Jance quotation. nd (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous; Snow globe- Birds of Prey. nd (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous- Stencil- Exit Wounds. nd (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Plaques; American Mystery Award. 1992 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Plaques; Friends of the Scottsdale Public Library, Inc. 1999 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Plaques; University of Arizona. 2000 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Plaques; Volkssporting Community. 2001 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Plaques; Women in Communication, Inc. 1996 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Computer; Dual Floppy Eagle. 1983